Hello everyone, I'm Eric. Today
in this video, I'll introduce
you to the concept of Object-Oriented Programming.
Finally, after so
many days of waiting, after we've
studied three chapters, today
we'll learn about OOP. OOP stands for
Object-Oriented Programming.
If you translate
this into Vietnamese, it means
Object-Oriented Programming, but
we often shorten it to OOP for
simplicity. In reality, we
have a term like this: at
the end of the day, meaning that no matter
how we code, whether we
code using Object-Oriented Programming
or not, this
program, this software, or this
application is just a collection of
C blocks, and our computer
doesn't understand the code blocks; it
only understands the commands running from top
to bottom. This is the meaning
of a program before we
know about OOP.  It's not
necessarily true that you need to know about
Object-Oriented Programming. Because
Object-Oriented Programming is just one of
many ways out there to
complete a program. For example,
I'm sure that anyone
who went to high school or
even middle school knew about the
Pasco programming language.
Nowadays, we teach
Python instead of
Pasco. I believe that
when you look at this image, many of
you will recognize this language, and this
is a block of code.
You can see that it's not
like how we used to write code.
You can see that we
revolve around
an object, which
is this class. At the same time,
we have opening and closing parenthesis like this.
You can feel that this
block of code wraps
around a function like this.
It's concise like this, instead of...
You use characters like "
Begin" and "End". You
see, it uses many "
Begin" and "End" characters, it's like
a sequence, right?
Back in the day, we used to have what we
called procedural programming or
structured programming.
Even if you studied Finance,
like React, we had function
programming, right? And
our method
here is object-oriented programming. So, the
first thing you need to know is that the method
doesn't matter; what matters is that
it solves your
problem effectively. That's
why we choose this
technology. I'm sharing
this first because we need to
understand that OP doesn't
solve all problems. There
will be
cases where OP doesn't solve them, but
we need to understand that as long
as our method
solves the problem, it solves it.  Okay,
so it will work. Here we
need to know a few advantages
of object-oriented programming compared to using other
methods. First,
with object-oriented programming,
we have the first characteristic:
our structure is very
clear. Second, we have the
ability to reuse code. Reusing
code like
this easily leads to problems, such as the
process of maintaining,
modifying, or even rewriting code, which makes it
easier for the
programmer. And finally, from
the beginning,
object-oriented programming is geared
towards applications – medium-sized applications,
large applications, or
complex applications. From the very beginning,
the initial designer/
author aimed for this purpose.
If these are the
things you need, then object-oriented programming is
probably the right choice.
We should learn this. The question is,
what the heck is "op"? When
we hear the name like this, the
first keyword that catches our eye
is "object."
If you translate "object" into
Vietnamese, it means "object." So,
surrounding this "op" is an
object. The
next question is,
what is an object? In reality, "op"
is how we simulate the real world—
our real world—
into a virtual program,
our computer program. All these things,
all
these objects, all the entities participating in
the program are the
key components that we need to
virtualize. To be more specific, let's take my website, "
Ask the IT People," as an example. Look at this "Ask the IT People" website of mine.
For example, if we
look at this website, we're
looking at it from the user's perspective.
We haven't even talked about the programmer's perspective yet.
You see, for
example, with the course function,
we need to design the courses,
right? And inside a course,
you see this: inside
this course, I have the title, the
knowledge you will learn, the
demo video, and the
course content. These are the
components of a course. So,
in our minds, let's
start by listing the first few lines.
For example, the list of courses
will include individual courses. A
course will have course content, a
title, a price, and a course outline.
This is how
you are simulating a real-world scenario
in your program
through object-oriented programming thinking.
The next question you'll
ask is, how do we do it?
How do we simulate it? Right?
In this video... I just want to
introduce you to the concept of
object-oriented programming.  I don't
want to go into too much detail, but
if
you happen to be interviewed later and they ask
you what Object-Oriented Programming is,
in the simplest way possible, I know
my learning method isn't
100% correct, but it's relatively accurate.
Object-oriented programming is
how we simulate
real-world entities into
our virtual programs,
into computer programs. That's
called Object-
Oriented Programming. Object-oriented programming has
advantages like this:
clear structure,
code reuse.
If you want to reuse
code, want easy maintenance,
easy modification, or
easy debugging, then
Object-Oriented Programming is what
you need, unlike
other styles such as
procedural programming or
structured programming.  Or perhaps even
function programming might
not meet
your needs here, so we'll learn
object-oriented programming, even though
Java will support function
programming later on. It's not that
it doesn't support it, but here
we're focusing on object-oriented programming. The
next question I'll answer is:
how can we apply
object-oriented programming?
We'll explore that together in the next video.